{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following two organelles look most alike structurally?", "opta": "Nucleus and vesicle", "optb": "Golgi apparatus and smooth endoplasmic reticulum ER", "optc": "Vacuole and cytoskeleton", "optd": "Lysosome and chloroplast", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In terms of basic cell structure, what do an elephant and an oak tree have in common?", "opta": "They both are eukaryotes", "optb": "They both have a cell nucleus", "optc": "They both have mitochondria", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Where in a eukaryotic cell, DNA can be found?", "opta": "Nucleus", "optb": "Mitochondrion", "optc": "Vacuole", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following structures is expected in a bacterium?", "opta": "Nucleus", "optb": "Plasma membrane", "optc": "Golgi apparatus", "optd": "Endoplasmic reticulum", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organelles is directly connected to the outer membrane of the nucleus in a eukaryotic cell?", "opta": "Mitochondrion", "optb": "Lysosome", "optc": "Golgi apparatus", "optd": "Endoplasmic reticulum", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microtubules, motor proteins, and actin filaments are all part of", "opta": "the mechanism of photosynthesis that occurs in chloroplasts", "optb": "the rough ER (endoplasmic reticulum) in prokaryotic cells", "optc": "the cytoskeleton of eukaryotic cells", "optd": "the process that moves small molecules across cell membranes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A certain cell organelle which is made of a double phospholipid bilayer that has many large pores in it, is most likely", "opta": "the nuclear envelope", "optb": "the plasma membrane", "optc": "the mitochondrion", "optd": "the cytoskeleton", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following cell organelles are expected to be associated with motor proteins?", "opta": "Smooth ER", "optb": "Vesicles", "optc": "Plasma membrane", "optd": "Chloroplasts", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Eukaryotic cells are more efficient than prokaryotes because their internal compartmentalization", "opta": "makes each compartment nutritionally independent of all others", "optb": "allows for specialization through the subdivision of particular tasks", "optc": "allows for specialization through merging of different tasks", "optd": "reduces overall cell size", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An organism's first line of defense against attack by an invader such as a virus or bacterium is usually", "opta": "to flee or hide", "optb": "its body wall", "optc": "a specific immune response", "optd": "a nonspecific immune response", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to the fluid mosaic model of cell membranes,", "opta": "the most common type of molecules in the membrane are proteins", "optb": "basic membrane structure results from how the proteins interact with water", "optc": "the membrane is a highly mobile mixture of phospholipids and proteins", "optd": "the unique properties of cell types are determined by their phospholipids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The simplest way to differentiate a prokaryotic cell from a eukaryotic one is to", "opta": "look for a plasma membrane", "optb": "see if a nucleus is present", "optc": "check for the presence of DNA", "optd": "determine if the cell is an entire organism or not", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the best criterion for deciding whether a cell is prokaryotic or eukaryotic?", "opta": "The cell came from a single-celled or multicelled organism", "optb": "The cell has a nucleus or not", "optc": "The cell has cytosol or not", "optd": "DNA is present in the cell or not", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysosomes are specialized vesicles in __________ that contain digestive enzymes for the breakdown of food. A related organalle known as a vacuole, which is found in __________ , also contains enzymes but in addition may act as a storage organelle for nutrients or water.", "opta": "animals; plants and fungi", "optb": "plants; animals and fungi", "optc": "plants and fungi; animals", "optd": "animals and plants; fungi", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The highly folded membranes found in such eukaryotic organelles as mitochondria and chloroplasts", "opta": "increase the surface area where key chemical processes can occur", "optb": "help the cell against physical damage", "optc": "make it possible to package large amounts of DNA within the cell", "optd": "assist with cell movement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about prokaryotes is false?", "opta": "Prokaryotic cells concentrate important materials for the cells survival", "optb": "The substance known as cytosol is found within the bacterial nucleus", "optc": "Prokaryotic cells are much smaller than most eukaryotic cells", "optd": "Ancient prokaryotes may have given rise to some eukaryotic organelles", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do dystrophin, utrophin, actin, and tubulin have to do with eukaryotic cell structure and function?", "opta": "They are components in the reactions of photosynthesis", "optb": "They all participate in the degradation of large amounts of ATP", "optc": "They all participate in the production of large amounts of ATP", "optd": "They are all embedded proteins in plasma membranes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the following cell organelles, it is expected to find the biochemical reactions that harness energy from the breakdown of sugar molecules to synthesize large amounts of ATP?", "opta": "Lysosome", "optb": "Vesicles", "optc": "Mitochondria", "optd": "Plasma membrane", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following macromolecules are found in the plasma membrane?", "opta": "Lipids and proteins only", "optb": "Lipids, proteins, and carbohydrates", "optc": "Proteins and carbohydrates only", "optd": "Proteins only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Clearly defined nucleus, mitochondria in a large central vacuole and chloroplasts, indicate the group of organisms from", "opta": "bacteria", "optb": "fungi", "optc": "plants", "optd": "animals", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are responsible causing the diseases?", "opta": "Pathogens", "optb": "T cells", "optc": "Lymphocytes", "optd": "Macrophages", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the following cell types more cellular detail can be observed using an electron microscope compared to a light microscope?", "opta": "Animal", "optb": "Bacterial", "optc": "Protist", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is present in both prokaryotes and eukaryotes?", "opta": "Lysosome", "optb": "Chloroplast", "optc": "Plasma membrane", "optd": "Vacuole", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}